# **Yiren Jian**

### PhD Student

Computer Science, Dartmouth College

🛘 yiren.jian.gr@dartmouth.edu 📗 😭 yiren-jian.github.io 📗 🖫 yiren-jian

My research spans a wide range of topics within the field of machine learning, focusing on computer vision, natural language processing and computational science. Specifically, my work involves the pre-training of generative visual-language models, the investigation of multi-modal sentence embeddings, the exploration of few-shot learning in both vision and language domains, as well as the application of AI and ML in scientific contexts.

### **Professional Experience**

#### Research Scientist Intern, ByteDance/TikTok AML

Bellevue, WA

Develop efficient generative visual-language models based on LLM.

June. 2023 - Sept. 2023

Advisor: Yunzhe Tao and Hongxia Yang

#### **Research Scientist Intern, Snap Research**

Palo Alto, CA

Develop neural speakers for affective image captioning.

June. 2022 - Sept. 2022

Advisor: Panos Achlioptas

#### **Research Scientist Intern, NEC Labs America**

Princeton, NJ

Develop physical-augmented ML models for precision immunotherapy.

June. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Advisor: Martin Rengiang Min

### Education

**Dartmouth College** 

Hanover, NH, USA

Doctor of Philosophy - Computer Science

Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2024 (expected)

Advisor: Soroush Vosoughi

The George Washington University

Washington DC, USA

Master of Science - Biophysics

Sept. 2015 - May. 2017

Advisor: Chen Zeng

#### **Huazhong University of Science and Technology**

Wuhan, China

Bachelor of Science - Physics

Sept. 2011 - May. 2015

Thesis advisor: Yi Xiao

#### **Publications**

#### [P18] SimVLG: Simple and Efficient Pretraining of Visual Language Generative Models

preprint, 2023

**Yiren Jian**, Tingkai Liu, Yunzhe Tao, Soroush Vosoughi, Hongxia Yang

#### [P17] Bootstrapping Vision-Language Learning with Decoupled Language Pre-training

Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2023, Spotlight)

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### [P16] Evaluation of DNA-protein complex structures using the deep learning method

Physical Chemistry and Chemical Physics, 2023

Chengwei Zeng<sup>#</sup>, **Yiren Jian**<sup>#</sup>, Chen Zhuo, Anbang Li, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

# [P15] Knowledge from Large-Scale Protein Contact Prediction Models Can Be Transferred to the Data-Scarce RNA Contact Prediction Task

preprint, 2023

**Yiren Jian**<sup>†</sup>, Chongyang Gao, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao, Soroush Vosoughi<sup>†</sup>

#### [P14] Evaluating Native-like Structures of RNA-protein Complexes Through the Deep Learning Method

Nature Communications, 2023

Chengwei Zeng<sup>#</sup>, **Yiren Jian**<sup>#</sup>, Soroush Vosoughi, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

#### [P13] Non-Linguistic Supervision for Contrastive Learning of Sentence Embeddings

Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2022)

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### [P12] T-Cell Receptor-Peptide Interaction Prediction with Physical Model Augmented Pseudo-Labeling

In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD 2022, Oral Presentation)

Yiren Jian, Erik Kruus, Martin Rengiang Min

#### [P11] Embedding Hallucination for Few-shot Language Fine-tuning

In Proceedings of the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACL 2022)

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### [P10] Contrastive Learning for Prompt-based Few-shot Language Learners

 $In \ Proceedings \ of the \ 2022 \ Conference \ of the \ North \ American \ Chapter \ of the \ Association \ for \ Computational \ Linguistics: \ Human \ Language$ 

Technologies (NAACL 2022)

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### [P9] Label Hallucination for Few-Shot Classification

Proceedings of the 36th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2022)

Yiren Jian, Lorenzo Torresani

#### [P8] MetaPix: Domain Transfer for Semantic Segmentation by Meta Pixel Weighting

Image and Vision Computing, 2021

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao

#### [P7] Task Meta-Transfer from Limited Parallel Labels

Meta-Learning Workshop at Neural Information Processing Systems, 2020

Yiren Jian, Karim Ahmed, Lorenzo Torresani

#### [P6] DIRECT: RNA Contact Predictions by Integrating Structural Patter

BMC Bioinformatics, 2019

**Yiren Jian**, Xiaonan Wang, Jiadi Qiu, Huiwen Wang, Zhichao Liu, Yunjie Zhao, Chen Zeng

# [P5] Trace, Machine Learning of Signal Images for Trace-Sensitive Mass Spectrometry: A Case Study from Single-Cell Metabolomics

Analytical Chemistry, 2019

Zhichao Liu, Erika P. Portero, **Yiren Jian**, Yunjie Zhao, Rosemary M. Onjiko, Chen Zeng, Peter Nemes

#### [P4] Design of Tat-activated Cdk9 Inhibitor

Journal of Peptide Research and Therapeutics, 2019

Yunjie Zhao, Hao Chen, Chenghang Du, Yiren Jian, Haotian Li, Yi Xiao, Mohammed Saifuddin, Fatah Kashanchi, and Chen Zeng

#### [P3] Rbind: Computational Network Method to Predict the Binding Sites of RNA Molecules

Bioinformatics, 2018

Kaili Wang<sup>#</sup>, **Yiren Jian**<sup>#</sup>, Huiwen Wang, Chen Zeng and Yunjie Zhao

#### [P2] Computational Study of Non-catalytic T-loop Pocket on CDK Proteins for Drug Development

Chinese Physics B, 2017

Huiwen Wang, Kaili Wang, Zeyu Guan, **Yiren Jian**, Ya Jia, Fatah Kashanchi, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

#### [P1] Network Analysis Reveals the Recognition Mechanism for Dimer Formation of Bulb-type Lectins

Scientific Report, 2017

Yunjie Zhao<sup>#</sup>, Yiren Jian<sup>#</sup>, Zhichao Liu, Hang Liu, Qin Liu, Chanyou Chen, Zhangyong Li, Lu Wang, H. Howie Huang, Chen Zeng

#### Patents\_

T-cell receptor repertoire selection prediction with physical model augmented pseudo-labeling (NEC Labs America)

### **Academic Services**

Invited Reviewer, International Conference on Learning Representations
Invited Reviewer, Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence
Invited Reviewer, Northern European Journal of Language Technology
Invited Reviewer, IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision
Invited Reviewer, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems
External Reviewer, Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics

## Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_\_

| 2019, 2021 <b>Graduate Teaching Assistant,</b> Deep Learning (graduate-level course)     | Dartmouth |
|--|-----------|
| 2021-2023 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning (graduate-level course)          | Dartmouth |
| 2018 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning (graduate-level course)               | Dartmouth |
| 2015-2016 <b>Graduate Teaching Assistant</b> . University Physics (undergraduate course) | GWU       |